Elani Streja, PhD, MPH

Phone: (818) 259-5525 | Email: strejaelani@gmail.com

PROFILE:

Real world evidence epidemiologist with 240+ publications in <u>Pubmed</u> (cited by 27,361 in <u>Google Scholar</u>) and 10+ years of experience leading diverse teams in developing research ideas, identifying and executing appropriate statistical strategies, implementing novel methods including AI/ML, interpreting results into clinically impactful presentations and reports, and submitting results leading to conference presentations and manuscripts. Excellent interpersonal and professional skills and driven towards team success.

EXPERIENCE:

Associate Center Director of Scientific and Technical Operations for the Veterans Affairs Cooperative Studies Program (CSP) Clinical Epidemiology Research Center (CERC) [GS14] (01/2022 - Present)

Connecticut Veterans Affairs Healthcare System

- Lead a team of 1 epidemiologist and 6 informaticists on data pulls from internal electronic medical record (EMR) (VA-VINCI) system and Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) claims system using SQL
- Oversee, instruct, and debug coding conducted by team members for statistical analysis using SAS, R, and Stata
- Instruct contractors on specifications for development of center standard operating procedures (SOPS) for appropriate data handling, analysis formatting, documentation, and reporting.
- Mentor team on development of appropriate, impactful, and clinically meaningful reporting to principal investigators and other external stakeholders
- Coordinate staffing, transitions, and project portfolio with center leadership
- Meet and work with principal investigators and external stakeholders to align project needs and address issues of team and project satisfaction
- Lead project protocol development, manuscript writing, and Internal Review Board (IRB) submissions
- Conduct intake with new and potentials of investigators on projects plans and development
- Manage portfolio of projects on comparative effectiveness of antiviral medication for COVID-19 in US Veterans using causal inference methodology in coordination with BARDA and FDA, treatments of glycemia in US Veteran patients, treatments of anti-viral medications in US Veterans with HIV, machine learning approaches to identify gulf war illness using survey data from the Million Veterans Program (MVP)

Health Science Specialist (07/2017 - 12/2021)

Long Beach Veterans Affairs Medical Center

- Supervised a team of 6 epidemiologists and analysts performing data abstraction, statistical analysis in SAS and STATA, and reporting on grant and pharmaceutical funded research on VA (including OMOP structured) databases
- Served as principal investigator for Astra Zeneca funded study on Hyperkalemia in US Veterans (May 2020-April 2022), served as corresponding author and conducted statistical analyses and revisions for manuscript submission.
- Awarded Research and Evaluators in Residence Award for the National Kidney Program (July 2019-July 2020), acted as researcher for National Kidney Program, Office of Specialty Care, and lead team on design, implementation, and updating of the chronic kidney disease factsheet on US Veterans
- Awarded Career Development Award [IK2CX001266-02] entitled "Lipid Profiles and Management in Chronic Kidney Disease", developed clinical research question, and led team on implementation of statistical analyses and manuscript authorship and submission
- Assisted with IRB and grant processing and VA data transfer requests

Research Scientist (01/2007 - 06/2017)

Harold Simmins Research Center

- Acted as site Co-investigator for Uo1-RFA-DK-13-008 Transition of Care in Chronic Kidney Disease and HSRD Io1-HX002680 VA Merit Therapeutic Interventions in Chronic Kidney Disease
- Was promoted from Staff Research Associate (Jan 2007- Nov 2012) to Assistant Statistician (Nov 2012 Feb 2014) to Faculty Project Scientist I (Feb 2014 Nov 2015) to Adjunct Assistant Professor (Nov 2015 July 2016)
- Conducted statistical analyses including Cox Regression, Logistic Regressions, Spline, Joint Modeling, Marginal Structural Models, and summary statistics using SAS and STATA and plotting in R and Sigma Plot on DaVita, United States Renal Data System (USRDS), Scientific Registry of Transplant Recipients (SRTR), CMS, Optum, and investigator created survey data
- Conducted data cleaning and data management of investigator created data sets
- Trained new employees on coding documentation, data organization, communications, and manuscript development

Phone: (818) 259-5525 | Email: strejaelani@gmail.com

Adjunct Associate Professor (06/2016 - Present)

University of California, Irvine Medical Center CA-Nephrology and Program of Public Health

- Mentored and assisted over 80 diverse medical, public health master's practicum, public health doctoral, and
 undergraduate students on development of research ideas, creation of research protocols, identification of
 statistical methodology, interpretation of results, generation of manuscripts, posters, and presentations, and
 submissions of grants and IRB protocols resulting in first authorship publications, dissertations, and conference
 postural and oral presentations
- Led trainings on programming in SAS and STATA, administrative processes for obtaining data, and conducting analyses on CMS
- Taught Introductory Epidemiology to 260 undergraduate students, Research Design to 7 epidemiology doctoral students, and Analysis of Public Health Data Using Statistical Software to 9 master's of public health students
- Served as guest lecturer in a class of 30 medical students speaking on chronic kidney disease epidemiology

Adjunct Assistant Professor (07/2018 - Present)

University of California, Los Angeles, Jonathan and Karin Fielding School of Public Health

- Taught Introductory Epidemiology to 200 incoming masters of public health students
- Served annually as guest lecturer of Cardiovascular Epidemiology on kidney disease and cardiovascular health
- Served annually on the review committee for students applying to the PhD in Epidemiology program
- Conducted statistical consulting for new researchers at the VA including consulting on data sources, power calculation, statistical and research methodology, and IRB submission

EDUCATION:

PhD	Epidemiology	University of California, Los Angeles	2012
MPH	Epidemiology	University of California, Los Angeles	2006
BS	Biochemistry	University of California, Davis	2000

SKILLS:

Programming/Scripting Languages: SAS, R, SQL, STATA, Python (experienced with both Pandas and NumPy), SAS

CERTIFICATION:

General Assembly Data Science Boot Camp 2019

PUBLICATIONS, GRANTS, AWARDS, AND MEMBERSHIPS:

Project List on GitHub